innovate
enable
icici lombard and cnbc tv 18 presents
india risk management awards risk
masterclass
now if the past year has taught us one
thing it is that the traditional
approach to risk management simply does
not work the global pandemic
fundamentally challenged how companies
identified assessed managed and
monitored risk tossing aside long-held
beliefs around security i.t resiliency
crisis management to name a few it's
also important that the crisis and
resilience teams integrated the lessons
learned from 2020 to maintain a higher
degree of flexibility and agility in
responding to as well as anticipating
the continuous curveballs thrown their
way now this can only be done
effectively by leveraging the right data
and technology tools so today's
masterclass focuses on the service
sector and how enterprise whip is being
redefined in a post covert 19
environment first up on the show now i
would like to welcome sahil kangotra
vice president corporate solutions group
icici lombard to share his insights into
how risk intelligence can be framed for
faster executive action sahil will also
talk about risk mitigation measures
companies need to take to prepare
themselves for such black swan events
in recent times all sectors have been
impacted pervasively by kobe 19
within service sector there are few
sectors like i.t
banking which has been suffered a little
lesser as compared to hospitality hotels
travel which has been effective
extensively
the pandemic situation has surely
created crisis but it has also helped us
prepare for such exposures in future
from a risk management perspective
corville would represent a shift from
frequent risk identification to great
risk management
in the past lack of data was a big issue
but today the necessary data is already
available with us which can help us
prepare for the future
companies which would be agile more
adaptive which surely succeed in future
for a long time managing enterprise risk
has been viewed as a compliance exercise
and many a times only to fulfill
banker's requirements the immediate
lesson of the crisis is that the process
in itself must be dynamic and should be
owned by the board of all the
organizations
so the entire thing needs to be
reinvented and i'm sure india risk
managers are ready to lead this change
so how do we see rich change in future
in my opinion i believe proactive risk
management will become top management's
priority
on-demand insights and real-time
reporting will replace spreadsheets
the interdependence of threats will be
essential as one event can have far
reaching impact across the entire
organization
a small cyber attack can lead to
business disruption it can lead to
business continuity supply chain
disruption a huge financial loss to the
company good will loss and so on in this
environment of cascading risk having a
360 degree view would be of great
importance you need to look at all the
threats across domains and understand
how they are interconnected and take
subsequent measures we at ics lombard
believe that we must act as risk advisor
for our clients and along with the right
product we continuously work toward
mitigating losses through value-add
services
for several second clients we work
closely with their ic teams of cyber
west to see how well they are prepared
when there is an actual cyber attack
we also work with their hr teams on
unique wellness offerings
to ensure overall health of the
organization
this surely would lead to less
absenteeism and lower hospitalization
thank you sahil for those valuable
insights next i would like to invite our
keynote speaker for the evening santosh
kumar nayar partner deloitte india and
santosh will be sharing with us the top
risk factors which impacted the service
industry over the last year and also his
company's top risk management strategies
it is perfectionary these days
to start any conversation on risk
management with the mention of the
pandemic so so let me do that as well
2020 has been a launch watershed
event
in our lives
default settings for all of us
has changed
nothing that we do or nothing that we
know
applies equally well
anymore and risk management has been no
exception
what is also important
is enterprises like never before have
realized the importance of resilience
that is their ability to withstand
unpredictability
to deal with such unpredictable
events
and to thrive
in such uncertain
environments
for the longest of times enterprises
have been focused on
short-term learning and related
objectives
and this has been based on the
assumption of
smooth and consistent
operation
and we know that the pandemic was a
wake-up call for all of us
the pandemic
really
rang a bell and challenged these
assumption on
consistent smooth
operating environment
if you will we at deloitte did a survey
uh towards the end of 2020
we covered close to 200 global
enterprises
and and 2000 cxos
and 6 out of every 10 respondents
seem to indicate that the pandemic is
not an outlier
you know which is not surprising
considering what we have gone through
which means that 60 percent of the
respondents believe
that such occurrences are par for course
they will continue to happen in the
future and probably
happen at a much higher
frequency
so so in a world which is changing
rapidly which is complex and disruptive
risk response time is extremely critical
right because
once the risk onsets the velocity of
such risks is going to be so high that
the enterprises may not have enough time
to respond and the hallmark of a good
resilient framework is that enterprises
will be able to cut down
on that response time and will be able
to respond to such emerging threats in a
much more agile and proactive manner
so if you look around us and we look at
the last couple of years especially
during the pandemic and post pandemic
you will see that the successful
organizations are the one
which have had a highly effective
resilience programs and these are all
entities which
made early investments
in the resilience activities the
resilience framework and the resilience
program
and these entities have benefited
because they've converted these crisis
events
into sustainable competitive advantage
as someone famously once said
never let a
crisis situation go go waste capitalize
on it and companies which have got this
resilience framework frameworks have
definitely capitalized
now what do we mean by effective
resilience frameworks
i think there are two parts to an
effective resilience framework
one is the ability to anticipate
and the second and equally important is
the competency to respond
and that is where risk intelligent
frameworks
come into play
now risk intelligence frameworks like
every other framework
is built upon people process technology
i am a firm believer that process and
technology are the easier parts
it is easily available most companies
have access to it and hence can be
implemented fairly quickly but unless
organizations get their people aspect
correct
it is very difficult to have an
effective and resilient risk management
program remember risk intelligence is
not just about
value preservation it is now more about
the value enhancement and value creation
thank you all for your time
have a good day
thank you satosh kumar for sharing with
us your valuable insights and strategies
ici lombard and cnbc tv 18 present india
risk management awards risk master class
next up on the show we have our panel
discussion so let's welcome our esteemed
guests who are waiting in the wing so to
speak and bring them on board starting
with saurabh lal cfo at ags transact
manoj rani partner head of india psionic
india
sanjay dutta chief underwriting
reinsurance and claims icici lombard
kamal khakar cfo of palace india
and bhaskaran and rao cfo bangalore
international airport thank you so much
gentlemen for joining us on the show
right so let's talk about enterprise
risk management and how companies are
orienting both themselves their own
strategy and how they are addressing it
with their clients and uh let me start
with sanjay dutta who is the chief
underwriting and reinsurance and claims
and i say lombard sanjay you know for
a large conglomerate such as yourself
and somebody who looks at risks so
closely
please share with us your thoughts about
how both internally as a company and
externally to your clients are you
taking a real look at you know
enterprise risk management in the post
covered era no uh i think uh no one
anticipated the family right you know
let's answer the scale of the
you know uh issue nobody the scale of
the risk which unfolded nobody was aware
of this uh uh so let's
give it to ourselves that no one had
this on their particular
you know in terms of their implant but
how people responded was the key issue
as you correctly asked and we you know
since we dealt with different sectors we
found that uh you know apart from the
usual sectors which got uh affected
because of uh you know the pandemic
directly affecting which is basically
travel and various other businesses like
you know uh airlines and all that you
know getting shut down because of uh the
other businesses you know uh kind of uh
were able to uh in a sense uh deal with
two issues one is this whole issue of uh
i mean um shutdown you know and this was
the first case where the entire thing
was shut down not due to natural
catastrophe whether there was physical
damage
due to you know some you know uh
something which was gone
let me come to you because you're the
cfo of ajs transact your you know one of
the largest payment solution providers
to banks to corporates particularly for
instance we all know as far as your atm
services are concerned you know how
quickly were you able to reorient what
were some of the major trends that you
observed and how are you preparing for
the future i think sanjay was absolutely
correct no one was prepared for this
kind of catastrophe but definitely as we
rightly said we were part of this
industry which is a financial industry
where the business continuity plan plays
a very very critical role the movement
such kind of instances happen but as
he's rightly also said the economy was
completely shut down the physical
movement was actually next to impossible
so definitely the moment that lockdown
was announced which was i could remember
it was around
25th of march 2020 and everyone was not
prepared or geared it was a one-day
knockdown which immediately was moved to
21 days of lockdown with the next
working day and as as you rightly said
we are part of the banking industry
where we have to replenish the atm on
daily basis or to process the
transactions with respect to all the
banks another transaction on daily basis
it was not an easy task for us but
definitely as you rightly said
the i would say the need is a mother of
all the invention so immediately our
ground staff was there our custodians
our engineers the sops were tweaked
immediately we got into hygiene make
mechanism where atm next week filter
check the transactions has to be
processed the work from home structure
was not a part of the routine businesses
the workforce structure was created
immediately from the next day onwards
the technology was part and brought into
picture and this helped us to navigate
those times um let me go with that
thought to uh you know somebody who
perhaps represents the hospitality or
rather the travel space and that's
bhaskaran rao as the cfo for bangalore
international airport which is one of
the busiest and perhaps also one of the
best managed airports you know one of
the things which is said is that
companies uh you know used to perhaps
pay lip service when it came to risk
management as in they would have some
sort of a team or some sort of a plan in
place but not really perhaps do more
than that in that sense you know how did
you as a company face this you know
calamitous situation not just of the
pandemic but of completely your business
drying up and when the second lockdown
came you had of course
some part of your business continuing to
run with all the additional protocols
and costs and investments involved thank
you paramita i mean you're absolutely
right we are one of those uh severely
impacted uh factor
by the kobit 19 pandemic uh you know
airlines and aviation sector have always
been tightly been managed but this
pandemic has taught us quite a few
things uh it's exposed uh some areas of
risk which which we were unprepared for
in a sense that
as you know aviation business
was growing at a phenomenal speed in
india and
almost all everybody was on expansion uh
not only not only the airports but even
airlines and cargo everybody were
increasing their capacity increasing
their capabilities we got to be very
conscious about all these
risk parameters but however there were
new risks that
we suddenly were faced with one was i
mean the top most i would say was a
traffic current traffic ladder reduction
and also
uh you know drying up of and you likely
mentioned the drying up of the
aeronautical and non-aeronautical
streams of uh cash flow uh revenues it
has led to quite a lot of cash flow
stress you know from a double digit
growth number we were suddenly in a
situation where 80 percent of our
revenues were drown
the resulting stress on cash flow
became one of the biggest risk of the
industry
and the lockdown and travel restrictions
imposed by states
fear of infection
brought this sector and along with the
sector
as you rightly mentioned the hospitality
and travel sector also to its knees and
almost a grinding halt
so this was one of the key risks that we
suddenly had to grapple with you know
for us there was no no work from home
for majority of our employees
and so we had to deal with uh
new protocols new procedure uh so that
you know they are they are they are uh
comfortable coming back to work and
absolutely
the employees really made uh you know
our staff were tremendous in that
actually as individuals we may have been
thinking my god you know the world has
exploded but at the same time these
critical services continued running uh
especially uh you know during uh the
second wave uh that we saw so i i think
bhaskar as you said rightly that you
know your industry was perhaps the
hardest hit and cash flow became an
important impediment not just for the
hospitality sector but perhaps for many
companies across verticals
you know you are representing palace
india which is a multinational
cooperation in that sense was would you
say being a multinational um were you
able to leverage on some of the
international support that you got i
mean from your parents company and how
were you able to mitigate some of those
risks what were the risks that you faced
in the domestic market and did the fact
that you know as a multinational were
you able to get additional support and
hence somewhat some stability uh during
the pandemic the uh support coming from
our the parent group and there i can say
that
in terms of the captive
business which you know our indian
legal entities engaged into we were
quite active into uh you know continuing
our business support towards our uh you
know the fellow entities abroad wherever
uh there was a
a lesser or uh not very uh significant
impact was there in the businesses we
were continuing to support
on those geographies like in the
engineering services
then coming to
our the challenges within india
when looking at our the demography of
top line we have the
services
uh in form of the support the
engineering and then the project
management so
we were kind of in a
i would say
a more responsive mode towards the
domestic challenges where we were
looking at that there are the critical
activities where it is absolutely not
possible to do a work from home
support example on the project
management aspect
and there how we were able to respond to
those challenges
and then
apart from the other support services uh
there we were able to
uh
continue our services in a way
which
i would say with the help of customer
and also with the help of suppliers
wherever we can uh able to uh support in
a
more uh
a practical way which is because
everybody was more or less in the same
situation so on that note let me go
across to manoj manoj you know as head
of you know psyonic india you're looking
at the financial services consulting
firm how do you react to some of the
observations that have been made so far
in the discussion and particularly use
it as a lens for the future all risks do
not sit on the balance sheet or fields
do not only sit on the balance
and to that extent i think gold was a
great i o you suddenly realize that you
you know sometimes the logistical risks
are far higher than what financial just
presented there were issues relating to
mental health there were issues relating
to human resources there were issues
relating to working from home you know
there are
instances where
certain parts of the businesses and
banks cannot be done from home there are
security issues trading for instance is
one derivative
writing is another and so on and so
forth but you had to find a solution
once you moved home you wrestled with
issues like you know is the data speed
far fast enough you have people living
in the distant suburbs in you know
versailles for instance do they have
uh you know sufficient electricity or
around the clock electricity
there have been different approaches to
this you know uh different institute
institutions have been felt different
uh
one institution has given inverters to
their employees and of course laptops
have become you know omnipresent from
typical desktops which a lot of
asset offices you very interesting i
think uh insight and let me go across uh
you know uh back to uh sanjay on this
point and sanjay you know you know is
how are you
sort of taking a real look at risk both
risk which is on the balance sheet and
risk which is off the balance sheet uh
do you think somebody need to sort of
establish a team with multiple heads
reporting to senior management i mean
what's the
form that the future of risk management
is going to take within companies for
instance in the financial services space
how do we prepare for
uh you know the you you know that was
the family right they learning from the
family
i think the one key thing is you know of
course the whole the risks are very you
know integrated and you have to look at
it holistically is the keeping the other
thing i think which is coming through
very strongly is that
you know we need to be
calm into you know
in terms of times of crisis and you know
they're very agitated or very very
anxious during peace times and it's time
to be anxious now how do you prepare for
the next one we can't you know we keep
learning you know all the time on how to
deal with the pandemic or economic and
being integrated
it's time to be in you know very very
anxious now that how we taking all the
learnings and putting it into practice
you know so we have you know i think all
of you you asked question earlier
learning from all the indian sectors
which we deal with i think they were
extremely calm they dealt with issues
very very
you know heroically foreign apart from
the hospital sector which of course were
heroin they all you know just
you know
found ways to
uh you know address the situation and
you remind you it will you're not indian
what you asked you know it was
absolutely very clear you know the
thinking on what is important and how do
i take care of all these including
inverters and you know employee safety
and so many other things which came into
the plate at one goal and we had to deal
with the that one having said that we
are coming back to your question it's
very important that
you know that we
integrate the sources of uh you know
build a framework very well then of
course you know you would need to uh you
know there will be times when everyone
will not have everything in the house
you will need to get specialists
you know so uh but it's you know idea is
for something someone who's not very
familiar with high level activities we
need to get you specialist well that's
all the time we have for questions on
masterclass today i would like to thank
the audience and the guests for being a
part of this very special session
icici lombard and cnbc tv 18 presents
india risk management awards risk master
class
[Music]
focus
innovate
enabled